Guide to the Gail and Stephen Rudin slavery collection, 1728-1973.
Rudin (Gail and Stephen) Slavery Collection,
- Series IV: Freedmen's Documents
  - Agent Advises Recipient of Efforts of Freedman's Bureau to Send Boys and Girls North to Good Families, March 3, 1867; Location: Washington, DC Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Rudin # S - 471
  - Two Thousand Freedmen Pleading for Emigration to Africa - American Colonization Society Appeal, February, 1868; Location: Washington, DC Format: Ptd DOC (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Rudin # S - 320
  - Freedman contract, January 24, 1870; Location: Alabama (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Rudin # S - 36
- Series V: General Orders
  - General Order No. 44 - Vessel cannot take away any person of color without a pass, June 21, 1862; Format: Ptd DOC (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Rudin # S - 63
  - General Order No. 1 - Emancipation Proclamation, January 2, 1863; Format: Ptd DOC (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Rudin # S - 114
  - General Orders #143 Marks the Beginning of Colored Troop Recruitment by the U.S. Army, May 22, 1863; Location: Washington Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 16, Folder 23)
    Rudin # S - 564
  - General Orders No. 127 - Civil war draft riots, along with a check, July 15, 1863; Format: Ptd DOC (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Rudin # S - 666
  - General Orders No. 138 re: Impressment of Slaves, October 24, 1863; Location: Richmond, VA Format: Ptd DOC (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Rudin # S - 203
  - General Orders No. 16 - authorizing payment of a bounty to new volunteers, November 18, 1863; Format: Ptd DOC (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Rudin # S - 769
  - General Orders No. 17 - recruiting volunteers, November 23, 1863; Format: Ptd DOC (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - General Orders No. 30 - Rations for Adults, January 1, 1864; Format: Ptd DOC (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Rudin # S -
  - General Orders No. 23 - Court martial of a white officer of African American infantry for misdeeds while intoxicated, February 15, 1864; Format: Ptd DOC (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - General Orders No. 44 and No. 125 - Food guidelines for troops, September 9, 1864; Format: Ptd Doc (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Rudin # S - 612
  - General Orders No. 66 - List of officers in "colored troops", October 27, 1864; Format: Ptd Doc (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Rudin # S - 664
  - General Orders No. 22 - New Regulations for the Conquered Citizens of Florida, May 24, 1865; Location: Jacksonville, Florida Format: Ptd DOC (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Rudin # S - 587
  - General Orders No. 26 - Freed slaves without jobs are ordered to work camp, June 13, 1865; Location: Jacksonville, Florida Format: Ptd Doc (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Rudin # S - 708
  - General Order No. 129 - Equal Treatment of Blacks, July 25, 1865; Location: Washington Format: Ptd DOC (Box 2, Folder 34)
    Rudin # S - 216
  - General Orders No. 9 - Food for the Freed Slaves, February 6, 1868; Location: Washington Format: Ptd DOC (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Rudin # S - 573
  - General Orders No. 37 - President Johnson grants amnesty and the restoration of rights except for the ability to own slaves, July 6, 1868; Format: Ptd Doc (Box 2, Folder 36)
    Rudin # S - 658
  - General Orders No. 50 - An Act to Continue the Relief of Freedmen and Refugees for Another Year, July 24, 1868; Location: Washington, DC Format: Ptd DOC (Box 2, Folder 37)
    Rudin # S - 567
- Series VI: Letters
  - Anxiety of purchasing slaves, April 13, 1791; Writer: Anthony Wayne Writer's location: South Carolina Addressee: Sharp Delany, Esq. Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 38)
    Rudin # S - 182
  - Notice to African American man to get out of town, May 14, 1791; Writer: Select men of Swanzey Writer's location: Swanzey, Massachussetts Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Rudin # S - 621
  - A Quaker bemoans his decision not to manumit his slave, June 13, 1795; Writer: William Gifford Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Rudin # S - 715
  - Shipping Slaves to Natchez in 1804, February 20, 1804; Location: Louisville, Kentucky Format: ALS (Box 16, Folder 24)
    Rudin # S - 345
  - Letter on behalf of the American Colonization Society, Docketed 1826; Writer: F. Scott Key Addressee: Lieutenant William Wister McKean Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 41)
    Rudin # S - 325
  - Letter regarding lack of freeman's papers for slave and her children, May 28, 1830; Writer: A. Campbell Writer's location: Walterborough, South Carolina Addressee: John W. Mitchell, Esq. Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 42)
    Rudin # S - 369
  - Legitimacy of slave marriage, December 7, 1832; Writer: William Wirt Addressee: William Rawle Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Rudin # S - 847
  - Account of the 1834 New York anti-abolitionist riots, July 20, 1834; Writer: Jane MacNeven Writer's location: New York City Addressee: Rosa P. MacNeven Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 44)
    Rudin # S - 602
  - Colonizing Africans in Africa, September 3, 1836; Writer: Henry Clay Writer's location: Kentucky Addressee: Samuel Gwatheny Robertson Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Rudin # S - 186
  - Letter Discusses Favorable Opportunities to Invest in Land and Slaves, September 5, 1839; Writer: Jno. PR Stone Writer's location: Plantation, Iberville Addressee: Captain John Overstreet Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 46)
    Rudin # S - 219
  - Slave owner expresses great affection for his slaves. He is reluctant to sell them to pay his debts, June 19, 1840; Writer: John F. Mosely Writer's location: Noxubee City, Mississippi Addressee: DM Rupell, Esq. Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 47)
    Rudin # S - 292
  - Louisiana Slave Revolt, August 20, 1841; Writer: H. Hinchy Writer's location: St. Francisville, Louisiana Addressee: BP Hinchy Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 48)
    Rudin # S - 545
  - Shipping Slaves to Liberia, January 28, 1842; Writer: W McLain Writer's location: Washington City Addressee: General Thomas Ward Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 49)
    Rudin # S - 315
  - NY Colonization Society Letter Regarding Returning Emancipated Slaves to Africa, May 11, 1843; Writer: AS Dodge Writer's location: New York Addressee: HS Noyes Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 50)
    Rudin # S - 363
  - Alabamian defends the intelligence of slaves, September 18, 1843; Writer: D. MacAuley Writer's location: Florence, Alabama Addressee: Rev. Robert C. Waterston Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 51)
    Rudin # S - 997
  - Letter from Former Slaveholder, explaining "I could never consent again to own slaves", July 10, 1845; Writer: James Jarman Writer's location: Cincinnati, Ohio Addressee: Captain John F. Hawkins Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 52)
    Rudin # S - 6
  - Abolitionist discusses the issues of the time, much anti-slavery content, July 24, 1845; Writer: Charles Francis Adams Writer's location: Quincy, Massachussetts Addressee: Charles Whipple Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 53)
    Rudin # S - 714
  - Discussion of commerce, opportunities for future independence, and the capture of an illegal American slave ship, October 3, 1845; Writer: Joseph Jenkins Roberts Writer's location: Monrovia, Liberia Addressee: Benjamin Coates Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 54)
    Rudin # S - 991
  - Offer to Pay Creditors with Slaves, October 27, 1845; Writer: Thomas Land Writer's location: Tchula, Mississippi Addressee: William R. Campbell, Esq. Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 291
  - Letter soliciting funds to set free two slaves unjustly returned to slavery, October 25, 1847; Writer:On behalf of Gamaliel Bailey Writer's location: Washington, DC Addressee: Salmon P. Chase Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 1018
  - Letter from Slave Anney to her former master (), February 5, 1848; Writer's Location: Georgia Format: ALS (Box 16, Folder 25)
    Rudin # S - 100
  - Letter from Rich Perkins, Jr. to Capt. Charles Anthony (letter carried by slave), June 23, 1849; Location: Virginia Format: ALS (Box 16, Folder 26)
    Rudin # S - 105
  - Underground Railroad and Southern Rights, June 30, 1849; Writer: Several authors Writer's location: Hayneville, Loundes County, Alabama Addressee: Hon. Charles Brown Format: MLS (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 284
  - Document giving permission for slave to marry, June 28, 1850; Writer: Charles A. Price Addressee: Captain Price Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 12
  - Owner of 12 slaves needs money to buy the husband of her soon to be emancipated slave, October 30, 1852; Writer: JB Penny Writer's location: New York Addressee: Aristarchus Champion Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 636
  - Slave Document, re: "Slave can't bear children and a not good investment", February 6, 1856; Location: Arkansas Format: ALS (Box 16, Folder 27)
    Rudin # S - 29
  - Man beats the Wrong Slave by Mistake, October, 1856; Writer: Thomas Della Torre Writer's location: Rosemill, Kentucky? Addressee: John C. Della Torre Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 598
  - Letter with sketch of enslaved Native American, January 28, 1857; Writer: Ned Writer's location: Plaisance, Louisiana Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 592
  - Examination of Slavery in Louisiana, March 28, 1858; Writer: Egbert Phelps Writer's location: Alexandria, Louisiana Addressee: Wightman Chapman Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 351
  - Elderly Woman Grieves Because her Slave Families Are to be Broken Up, April 20, 1858; Writer's location: Baldwin County, Georgia Addressee: EP Peek Format: AL (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 341
  - Letter Describing Slaves Loading Cotton at the Alabama River, November 25, 1858; Writer: LH Potter Writer's location: Mobile, Alabama Addressee: Adaline Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Rudin # S - 269
  - House Servant Gets Married, November 28, 1858; Writer: Francis Writer's location: Cheraw, South Carolina Addressee: Lizzie Warsen (?) Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Rudin # S - 342
  - Slave auctioneer and his family hope to meet his former slave, July 18, 1859; Writer: Hutson Lee Writer's location: Charleston, South Carolina Addressee: Bolling Hall Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 839
  - Two letters reflecting on slavery's hold on the south, November 17, 1859 and April 1, 1860; Writer: Robert Crist Writer's location: Natchez, Mississippi Addressee: Father Format: ALS (Box 40, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 994
  - Slave letter to mother, November 19, 1859; Writer: Comfort Jany Writer's location: Georgia Addressee: Mother Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Rudin # S - 73
  - Letter Pertaining to the slave conjoined twins, Millie and Christine, May 11, ca. 1860; Writer: CV Moore Writer's location: Marrietta, Georgia Addressee: Louisa Shelton Format: ALS (Box 40, Folder 13)
    Rudin # S - 372
  - Hanging Abolitionists and slaves in Texas, August 12, 1860; Writer: Gramville Cornutt, James Cornutt Writer's location: Palopinto County, Texas Addressee: Father Format: ALS (Box 40, Folder 14)
    Rudin # S - 233
  - Content on African American man gets revenge over a rebel who intimidated and beat him, September 23, 1860; Writer: Lewis Sims Addressee:Courtney (wife) Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Rudin # S - 625
  - Secessionists Ordered Out of Washington, May 21, 1861; Writer: Order of the guard Writer's location: Washington, D.C. Addressee: Dr. J Warring Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Rudin # S - 212
  - Soldier Writes Requesting Spyglass, Compass, Wine, etc. and has Taken to Slave Catching, June 2, 1861; Writer: JF Pierson Writer's location: Camp Dix, Ft. Monroe Addressee: Father Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Rudin # S - 488
  - Cavalryman Instructs Wife on How to Care for Their Slaves, August 29, 1861; Writer: Sgt. Leonard Williams Writer's location: Bacon Race Church, Virginia Addressee: Wife Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Rudin # S - 361
  - Letter Describes Rickett's Trip to Annapolis, the Wounded Soldiers and an Arrest of an African American for Attempting to Poison Soldiers with Rum, August 31, 1861; Writer:Wm. Ricketts Writer's location: Annapolis, Maryland Addressee: Father and mother Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Rudin # S - 551
  - Talking with the slaves, envelope is a patriotic cover, November 25, 1861; Writer: Lester C. Wilcox Writer's location: White Sulphur Springs, Colorado Addressee: Mary Wilcox Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Rudin # S - 609
  - Four letters, describing playing a trick on a slave, experiences in the military, and the home front, November 3, 1861-December 22, 1862; Writer: C Personius, Ellie Personius Writer's location: New York Addressee: Family Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Rudin # S - 707
  - Garrison condemns slavery, writes of his career in the abolitionist movement, and the effect of the Civil War on slavery. With Carte-de-visite, December 20, 1861; Writer: William Lloyd Garrison Writer's location: Boston, Massachussetts Addressee: Maria Mariott Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Rudin # S - 774
  - Soldier describes Christmas sport of African Americans running in sack race, January 2, 1862; Writer: Corp. John B. Green Writer's location: Ship Island, Mississippi Addressee: Brother and sister Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Rudin # S - 238
  - Content Includes Whipping and White Women Kissing Slave Children, February 26, 1862; Writer: Newman Whipple Storer Writer's location: Camp Suffolk, Virginia Addressee: Everett Storer Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Rudin # S - 384
  - Confederate Officer gives his wife instructions if the enemy were to come, including sending the slaves south to be hired out, March 20, 1862; Writer: Captain George Bouton Writer's location: Yorktown, Virginia Addressee: Lucetta Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Rudin # S - 498
  - Letter hoping for end of slavery, April 8, 1862; Writer's location: New Haven, Connecticut Addressee: Mary Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Rudin # S - 599
  - Letter Discusses a "White Negro" and Contraband, April 20, 1862; Writer: Frederick Ranger Writer's location: Bivouac Falmouth, Virginia Addressee: Wife Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Rudin # S - 275
  - Pricing of cotton and hiring field hands at low wages, April 28, 1862; Writer: Gibbs and Co. Writer's location: Charleston, South Carolina Addressee: Messrs. Kerby and Wilson Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Rudin # S - 723
  - Letter regarding dancing African Americans, July 11, 1862; Writer: John Beach Writer's location: Moscow, Tennessee Addressee: Mother Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Rudin # S - 877
  - Writes of a Black Church Service and a Description of the Preacher, July 28, 1862; Writer: Frederick Ranger Writer's location: Falmouth, Virginia Addressee: Wife Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 29)
    Rudin # S - 595
  - Letter describing slaves crossing lines at night and getting a 'piece of cold lead', September 10, 1862; Writer: David W. Poak Writer's location: Jackson, Tennessee Addressee: SJ Poak Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 30)
    Rudin # S - 393
  - African Americans driving mules and horses in Philadelphia, September 19, 1862; Writer: William T. Lewis Writer's location: Near Philadelphia, Pennsylvania Addressee: Parents Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 31)
    Rudin # S- 662
  - Soldier describes hanging runaway slave on tree, September 23, 1862; Writer: David Brett Writer's location: Arlington Heights, Virginia Addressee: Wife Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 32)
    Rudin # S - 661
  - Man Tells Father to Save the Slaves, November 24, 1862; Writer: WA Goodman Writer's location: Huntsville, Alabama Addressee: Father Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 33)
    Rudin # S - 308
  - Letter regarding slaves happy to have their city saved, December, 1862; Writer: Charles Wallis Writer's location: Newbern, North Carolina Addressee: Allen (brother) Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 34)
    Rudin # S - 450
  - Union soldier observes his first freedmen Christmas, December 26, 1862; Writer: Samuel Bliss Writer's location: Port Royal Beauford Addressee: Wife Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 35)
    Rudin # S - 683
  - Soldier writes, "Whites and Blacks Cannot Live together as equals...", January 1, 1863; Writer: William H. Mozier Writer's location: Murfreesboro, Tennessee Addressee: Cousin Elvira Harrison Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 36)
    Rudin # S - 656
  - Soldier shares his thoughts on slaves and Lincoln, February 17, 1863; Writer: Sylvester O'Dare Writer's location: Falmouth, Virginia Addressee: Parents Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 37)
    Rudin # S - 487
  - Confederate soldier fears the federals have caught his slave, February 25, 1863; Writer: Robert M. Rucker Writer's location: Tullahoma Addressee: Mother Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 38)
    Rudin # S - 756
  - Content on African American troops, March 4, 1863; Writer: Paul S. Mauk Writer's location: Beaufort, South Carolina Addressee: Friend Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 39)
    Rudin # S - 178
  - Sickness in camp, Africans in camp dancing and cooking, April 25, 1863; Writer: Charles Morfoot Writer's location: Murfreesboro, Tennessee Addressee: Wife and children Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 40)
    Rudin # S - 722
  - Lieutenant writes that he is strongly in favor of "making the Negroes soldiers", June 7, 1863; Writer: CEW Writer's location: Folly Island, South Carolina Addressee: Brother Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 41)
    Rudin # S - 770
  - Describes the 3 days of riots following the new draft laws forcing men to join the army, July 17, 1863; Writer: Maria Writer's location: New York Addressee: J.J. Mitchell Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 42)
    Rudin # S - 848
  - News of the draft riots in New York, July 26, 1863; Writer: Emeline Writer's location: New York Addressee: Oscar F. Sammis Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 43)
    Rudin # S - 724
  - Preparing for Yankee Raids in Georgia and Sending a African Boy, August 25, 1863; Writer: Thomas Warthen Writer's location: Camp Gordons Brigade Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 44)
    Rudin # S - 539
  - Impoverished slaves hope to return to their master - Master hopes Union soldiers will allow her to rebuild., September 3, 1863; Writer: Sarah D. Partee Writer's location: Vicksburg Addressee: James B. McPherson Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 45)
    Rudin # S - 201
  - Discusses guerrillas, man bought and sold three times, hundreds made to work on fortifications, and humorous hospital incident, September 10, 1863; Writer: Charles D. Garlick Writer's location: Portsmouth, Virginia Addressee: Parents Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 46)
    Rudin # S - 946
  - Letter regarding colored troops, September 13, 1863; Writer: George Beidelman Writer's location: Camp William Penn, Pennsylvania Addressee: Father Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 47)
    Rudin # S - 86
  - Slavery letter: the second portion of the letter describes "the Iron Ring taken from the slave girl's neck" with a hand drawn illustration of the Slave Collar. The letter continues "If this is not an argumentum ad hominem for the conversion of unbelievers, none can be devised for them. They must be wilfully blind.", October 8, 1863; Writer: Nath'l Writer's location: Boston, Massachusetts Addressee: Mary Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 47a)
    Rudin # S - 1049
  - Describing Vicksburg after its capture, noting especially the behavior of white civilians and freed slaves, October 16, 1863; Location: Vicksburg, Mississippi Format: ALS (Box 16, Folder 28)
    Rudin # S - 845
  - Blackmailing free African Americans to avoid army conscription, November 17, 1863; Writer: Lt. Colonel Don Albert Pardee Writer's location: Baton Rouge, Louisiana Addressee: Captain Fordham Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 922
  - Colored troops capture Major Barrows, a noted guerilla, eleven prisoners, and confiscate 500 contraband slaves, November 29, 1863; Writer: Eugene Bates Writer's location: Camp near Norfolk, Virginia Addressee: Mother Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 624
  - Writes of Soldier's Game - Putting an African American in Blanket and Throwing Him Up in the Air, January 22, 1864; Writer: Elbridge G. Pond Writer's location: Morehead City, North Carolina Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 380
  - Slave owner Accuses an Overseer of Brutality, Causing Slaves to Run Away, March 26, 1864; Writer: William H. Kennedy Writer's location: Stantonsburg, North Carolina Addressee: Messrs. RR and JL Bridges and Co. Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 544
  - Letter and Lease Pertaining to School and Church for Colored People Under Government Supervision, April 20, October 31, 1864; Writer: RP Buckland Writer's location: Headquarters, District of Memphis, Tennessee Addressee: Format: MDocS, ALS (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 451
  - Letter with Content on Civil War and Slavery, April 22, 1864; Writer: OM Legate Writer's location: Alexandria, Virginia Addressee: Nancy BL Severance Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 366
  - Letter concerning contrabands and colored troops, May 22, 1864; Writer: William H. Nichols Writer's location: Camp Barry, Washington, DC Addressee: Friends Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 716
  - Slave-Carried Letter - Soldier Sending Boy for His Boots, May 28, 1864; Writer: Writer's location: Atlanta, Georgia Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 438
  - Writes About The Slave Quarters, June 28, 1864; Writer: Alfred S Roe Writer's location: Petersburg, Virginia Addressee: Parents and brothers Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 390
  - Male nurse writes of death of a soldier, and a "negro dancing toy", August 5, 1864; Writer: Virgil E. Connor (?) Writer's location: Washington, DC Addressee: Sister Lind Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Rudin # S - 878
  - African American cavalry fight, January 30, 1865; Writer: Richard Walton Writer's location: Fort Powhattan Addressee: Sallie Walton Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Rudin # S - 623
  - Black Confederate soldier writes to his master, February 18, 1865; Writer: Aabram Writer's location: Petersburg, Virginia Addressee: Master Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 797
  - Watson does not accept fighting along side Africans in the army, February 23, 1865; Writer: Thomas Watson Writer's location: Camp Pickets Division Addressee: Major Austin Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Rudin # S - 899
  - Newly freed slaves join the march to Danville and compliment the Union soldiers, April 28, 1865; Writer: Lewis Foster Writer's location: Danville, Virginia Addressee: Mother Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Rudin # S - 917
  - African caught thieving is forced to run through a guantlet of other men and nearly clubbed to death, May 25, 1865; Writer: Edward Flagg Writer's location: Camp at Richmond, Virginia Addressee: Father and mother Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Rudin # S - 626
  - Rules to be Followed by the Military in Administering Control of the Florida Plantations, Planters and the Freedmen. Also, Rules Provided for the Application of the Amnesty Oath., July 15, 1865; Writer: AC Pretz Writer's location: Tallahassee, Florida Addressee: Sagendorph Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Rudin # S - 410
  - Gilmore is asked to aid in the collection of confiscated confederate cotton, September 4, 1865; Writer: JC Callicot Writer's location: Charleston, South Carolina Addressee: General Gilmore Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Rudin # S - 657
  - Newly Freed Slaves Fare Poorly in Tennessee After the War, October 8, 1865; Writer's location: Clarksville, Montgomery County, Tennessee Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Rudin # S - 218
  - Plantation owners tell of problems with newly freed slaves, December 10, 1865; Writer: Peter WEir Writer's location: Warsaw, Sumter County, Alabama Addressee: Brother Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Rudin # S - 1023
  - Andrew Jackson vetoes the rights act of 1866, March 29, 1866; Writer: Samuel Jackson Randall Writer's location: Washington, DC Addressee: Adam John Glossbrenner Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Rudin # S - 689